A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Organizational and Employment History, Accession 2018:041 FA743
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Organizational and Employment History, Accession 2018:041
1953-2008
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA743
4.41 Cubic Feet 12 boxes (11 document containers and 1 half document container)
Scope and Contents
Contains Ford Foundation organization charts, staff directories, biographies of staff (including employment and educational histories), and staff photographs.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This material was transferred to RAC in 2018 and 2021 by the Ford Foundation and ingested by RAC as Accessions 2018:041 and 2021:022.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into four series:
1. Organization Charts, 1990-2006
2. Organization Charts - Information Services, 1970-2007
3. Staff Biographies and Directories, 1963-2008
4. Staff Pictures, undated
Ford Foundation
- Organization Charts, 1990-2006; 1; 1.14 Cubic Feet 3 letter document boxes
  - Organization Charts - Fiscal Year 1990, 1990 February (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Office of the President
    Office of Communications
    Office of Human Resources
    USIAP Grants Administration
    DCP Grants Administration
    Urban Poverty Program
    Human Rights and Governance Program
    International Affairs Program
    Program Related Investments
    Rural Poverty and Resources Program
    Program Division
    Education and Culture Program
    Asia Programs
    Bangladesh
    China
    India, Nepal, and Sri Lanka
    Southeast Asia
    Africa and Middle East Programs
    Eastern and Southern Africa
    Middle East and North Africa
    West Africa
    Latin America and Caribbean Programs
    Andean Region and the Southern Cone
    Brazil
    Mexico and Central America
    Office of the Secretary, Legal, Financial and Administrative Services
    Internal Audit
    Office of the General Counsel
    Office of the Secretary
    Grants Processing
    Administrative Services
    Building Services
    Management Information Systems
    Information Services
    Archives
    Library
    Communications Services
    Information Resources Units
    Financial Services
    Office of the Comptroller
    Master Custodian Support Group
    Investment Division
    Equity Investments
    Fixed Income Investments
    Special Investments
    Investment Administration
  - Organization Charts - Fiscal Year 1991, 1990 October-1991 July (Box 1, Folder 2)
    7-91 --
    Office of the Vice President Program Division
    Governance and Public Policy Program
    Rights and Social Justice Program
    Building Servicess
    Information and Records Units
    4/91 --
    1/91 --
    10/90 --
  - Organization Charts - Fiscal Year 1992 (2 folders), 1991 October-1992 July (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
    Folder 3: - 7/92 --
    Reproductive Health and Population Program
    South Africa and Namibia Program
    3/92 --
    Southeast Asia; Bangladesh
    Folder 4: 1/92 --
    10/91 --
  - Organization Charts - Fiscal Year 1993, 1992 November-December (Box 1, Folder 5)
    11/92 -- Office of the President
  - Organization Charts - Fiscal Year 1994 (4 folders), 1993 October-1994 August (Box 1, Folder 6-9)
    Folder 6:) - 10/93 -- Office of the President; Office of Communications; Office of Human Resources; Program Division; Office of the Vice President Program Division; USIAP Grants Administration; DCP Grants Administration; Urban Poverty Program; Reproductive Health and Population Program; Governance and Public Policy Program; Rights and Social Justice Program; International Affairs Program; Education and Culture Program; Program Related Investments; Rural Poverty and Resources Program; Asia Programs; India, Nepal, and Sri Lanka; Southeast Asia; Bangladesh; China; Africa and Middle East Programs; Eastern and Southern Africa; West Africa; Middle East and North Africa; South Africa and Namibia Program; Latin America and Caribbean Programs; Brazil; Mexico and Central America; Andean Region and the Southern Cone; Office of the Secretary, Legal, Financial and Administrative Services; Internal Audit; Office of the General Counsel; Office of the Secretary; Grants Processing; Individual Grants; Correspondence Control; Administrative Services; Facilities Management; Management Information Systems; Information Services; Archives; Library; Communications Services; Information and Records Units; Financial Services; Office of the Vice President; Fixed Income Investments; Equity Investments Research and Venture Capital; Equity Investments Portfolio Management; Investment Administration
    Folder 7:) 1/94 -- Office of the President; Office of Communications; Office of Human Resources; Program Division; Office of the Vice President Program Division; USIAP Grants Administration; DCP Grants Administration; Urban Poverty Program; Reproductive Health and Population Program; Governance and Public Policy Program; Rights and Social Justice Program; International Affairs Program; Education and Culture Program; Program Related Investments; Rural Poverty and Resources Program; Asia Programs; India, Nepal, and Sri Lanka; Southeast Asia; Bangladesh; China; Africa and Middle East Programs; Eastern and Southern Africa; West Africa; Middle East and North Africa; South Africa and Namibia Program; Latin America and Caribbean Programs; Brazil; Mexico and Central America; Andean Region and the Southern Cone; Office of the Secretary, Legal, Financial and Administrative Services; Internal Audit; Office of the General Counsel; Office of the Secretary; Grants Processing; Individual Grants; Correspondence Control; Administrative Services; Facilities Management; Management Information Systems; Information Services; Archives; Library; Communications Services; Information and Records Units; Financial Services; Investment Management Office of the Vice President; Fixed Income Investments; Equity Investments Research and Venture Capital; Equity Investments Portfolio Management; Investment Administration; Office of the Comptroller; Master Custodian Support Group; Investment Division; Equity Investments; Fixed Income Investments; Special Investments; Investment Administration
    Folder 8:) Office of the President; Office of Communications; Office of Human Resources; Program Division; Office of the Vice President Program Division; USIAP Grants Administration; DCP Grants Administration; Urban Poverty Program; Reproductive Health and Population Program; Governance and Public Policy Program; Rights and Social Justice Program; International Affairs Program; Education and Culture Program; Program Related Investments; Rural Poverty and Resources Program; Asia Programs; India, Nepal, and Sri Lanka; Southeast Asia; Bangladesh; China; Africa and Middle East Programs; Eastern and Southern Africa; West Africa; Middle East and North Africa; South Africa and Namibia Program; Latin America and Caribbean Programs; Brazil; Mexico and Central America; Andean Region and the Southern Cone; Office of the Secretary, Legal, Financial and Administrative Services; Internal Audit; Office of the General Counsel; Office of the Secretary; Grants Processing; Individual Grants; Correspondence Control; Administrative Services; Building Services; Management Information Systems; Information Services; Archives; Library; General Services; Information and Records Units; Financial Services; Investment Management Office of the Vice President; Fixed Income Investments; Equity Investments Research and Venture Captial; Equity Investments Portfolio Management; Investment Administration
    Folder 9:) 8/94 -- Office of the President; Office of Communications; Office of Human Resources; Program Division; Office of the Vice President Program Division; Grants Administration and Operations; Grants Administration; Urban Poverty Program; Reproductive Health and Population Program; Governance and Public Policy Program; Rights and Social Justice Program; International Affairs Program; Education and Culture Program; Program Related Investments; Rural Poverty and Resources Program; Asia Programs; India, Nepal, and Sri Lanka; Southeast Asia; Bangladesh; China; Africa and Middle East Programs; Eastern and Southern Africa; West Africa; Middle East and North Africa; South Africa and Namibia Program; Brazil; Latin America and Caribbean Programs; Mexico and Central America; Andean Region and the Southern Cone; Office of the Secretary, Legal, Financial and Administrative Services; Internal Audit; Office of the General Counsel; Office of the Secretary; Grants Processing; Individual Grants; Correspondence Control; Administrative Services; Facilities Management; Management Information Systems; Information Services; Archives; Library; General Services; Information and Records Units; Financial Services; Investment Management Office of the Vice President; Fixed Income Investments; Equity Investments Research and Venture Capital; Equity Investments Portfolio Management; Investment Administration; Facilities Management
  - Organization Charts - Fiscal Year 1995 (4 folders), 1994 November-1995 August (Box 1, Folder 10, Box 2, Folder 11-13)
    Folder 10:) 11/94 -- Office of Communications; Office of Human Resources; Program Division; Office of the Vice President Program Division; Grants Administration and Operations; Grants Administration; Urban Poverty Program; Reproductive Health and Population Program; Governance and Public Policy Program; Rights and Social Justice Program; International Affairs Program; Education and Culture Program; Program Related Investments; Rural Poverty and Resources Program; Asia Programs; India, Nepal, and Sri Lanka; Southeast Asia; Bangladesh; China; Africa and Middle East Programs; Eastern and Southern Africa; West Africa; Middle East and North Africa; South Africa and Namibia Program; Latin America and Caribbean Program; Brazil; Mexico and Central America; Andean Region and the Southern Cone; Office of the Secretary, Legal, Financial, and Administrative Services; Internal Audit; Office of the General Counsel; Office of the Secretary; Grants Processing; Grants to Organizations; Individual Grants; Correspondence Control; Administrative Services; Facilities Management; Management Information Systems; Information Services; Archives; Library; General Services; Information and Records Units; Financial Services; Investment Management Office of the Vice President; Fixed Income Investments; Equity Investments Research and Venture Capital; Portfolio Management; Investment Administration
    Folder 11:) 2/95 -- Office of the President; Office of Communications; Office of Human Resources; Program Division; Office of the Vice President Program Division; Grants Administration; Grants Administration; Urban Poverty Program; Reproductive Health and Population Program; Governance and Public Policy Program; Rights and Social Justice Program; International Affairs Program; Education and Culture Program; Program Related Investments; Rural Poverty and Resources Program; Asia Programs; India, Nepal, and Sri Lanka; Southeast Asia; Bangladesh; China; Africa and Middle East Programs; Eastern and Southern Africa; West Africa; Middle East and North Africa; South Africa and Namibia Program; Latin America and Caribbean Program; Brazil; Mexico and Central America; Andean Region and the Southern Cone; Office of the Secretary, Legal, Financial, and Administrative Services; Internal Audit; Office of the General Counsel; Office of the Secretary; Grants Processing; Grants to Organizations; Individual Grants; Correspondence Control; Administrative Services; Facilities Management; Management Information Systems; Information Services; Archives; Library; General Services; Information and Records Units; Financial Services; Investment Management Office of the Vice President; Fixed Income Investments; Equity Investments Research and Venture Capital; Portfolio Management; Investment Administration
    Folder 12:) -- Office of the President; Office of Communications; Office of Human Resources; Program Division; Office of the Vice President Program Division; Grants Administration and Operations; Grants Administration; Grants Administration; Urban Poverty Program; Reproductive Health and Population Program; Governance and Public Policy Program; Rights and Social Justice Program; International Affairs Program; Education and Culture Program; Program Related Investments; Rural Poverty and Resources Program; Asia Programs; India, Nepal, and Sri Lanka; Southeast Asia; Bangladesh; China; Africa and Middle East Programs; Eastern and Southern Africa; West Africa; Middle East and North Africa; South Africa and Namibia Program; Latin America and Caribbean Program; Brazil; Mexico and Central America; Andean Region and the Southern Cone; Office of the Secretary, Legal, Financial, and Administrative Services; Internal Audit; Office of the General Counsel; Office of the Secretary; Grants Processing; Grants to Organizations; Individual Grants; Correspondence Control; Administrative Services; Facilities Management; Management Information Systems; Information Services; Archives; Library; General Services; Information and Records Units; Financial Services; Investment Management Office of the Vice President; Fixed Income Investments; Equity Investments Research and Venture Capital; Equity Investments Portfolio Management; Investment Administration
    Folder 13:) -- Office of the President; Office of Communications; Office of Human Resources; Program Division; Office of the Vice President Program Division; Grants Administration and Operations; Grants Administration; Grants Administration; Urban Poverty Program; Reproductive Health and Population Program; Governance and Public Policy Program; Rights and Social Justice Program; International Affairs Program; Education and Culture Program; Program Related Investments; Rural Poverty and Resources Program; Asia Programs; India, Nepal, and Sri Lanka; Southeast Asia; Bangladesh; China; Vietnam; Africa and Middle East Programs; Eastern and Southern Africa; West Africa; Middle East and North Africa; South Africa and Namibia Program; Latin America and Caribbean Program; Brazil; Mexico and Central America; Andean Region and the Southern Cone; Office of the Secretary, Legal, Financial, and Administrative Services; Internal Audit; Office of the General Counsel; Office of the Secretary; Grants Processing; Grants to Organizations; Individual Grants; Correspondence Control; Administrative Services; Facilities Management; Management Information Systems; Information Services; Archives; Library; General Services; Information and Records Units; Financial Services; Investment Management Office of the Vice President; Fixed Income Investments; Equity Investments Research and Venture Capital; Equity Investments Portfolio Management; Investment Administration
  - Organization Charts - Fiscal Year 1998 (2 folders), 1997 October-1998 May (Box 2, Folder 14-15)
    Folder 14:) Office of the President; Office of Communications; Program Division; Office of the Vice President Asset Building and Community Development; Community and Resource Development; Economic Development; Human Development and Reproductive Health; Office of Vice President -- Education, Media, Arts, and Culture; Office of the Vice President Peace and Social Justice; Governance and Civil Society Program; Human Rights and International Cooperation Program; Office of Organizational Services; Office of Management Services; Grants Administration and Operations; Grants Administration - EMAC; Grants Administration - PSJ; Grants Administration - Assets; India, Nepal, and Sri Lanka; Indonesia; The Philippines; China; Vietnam and Thailand; Russia and Eastern Europe; Andean Region and the Southern Cone; Mexico and Central America; Brazil; Eastern and Southern Africa; Middle East and North Africa; South Africa and Namibia Program; West Africa; Office of the Secretary, Legal, Human Resources, Financial and Administrative Services; Internal Audit; Office of the General Counsel; Office of the Secretary; Grants Processing; Grants to Organizations; Individual Grants; Correspondence Control; Administrative Services; Facilities Management; Management Information Systems; Information Services; Archives; Records Services; Library; General Services; Information and Records Units; Financial Services; Office of Human Resources; Investment Management Office of the Vice President; Fixed Income Investments; Private Equity; Equity Investments; Investment Administration; Education, Knowledge, and Religion; General Managmement
    Folder 15:) -- Program Division; OVP -- Education, Media, Arts and Culture; Mexico and Central America; Office of the President; Office of Communications; Program Division; OVP -- Asset Building and Community Development; Community and Resource Development; Economic Development; Human Development and Reproductive Health; OVP -- Education, Media, Arts, and Culture; Education, Knowledge, and Religion; Media, Arts and Culture; Office of the Vice President Peace and Social Justice; Governance and Civil Society Program; Human Rights and International Cooperation Program; Office of Organizational Services; Office of Management Services; Grants Administration and Operations; Grants Administration - EMAC; Grants Administration - PSJ; Grants Administration - Assets; Grants Administration; India, Nepal, and Sri Lanka; Indonesia; The Philippines; China; Vietnam and China; Russia and Eastern Europe; Andean Region and the Southern Cone; Mexico and Central America; Brazil; Eastern and Southern Africa; Middle East and North America; South Africa and Namibia Program; West Africa; Office of the Secretary, Legal, Human Resources, Financial and Administrative Services; Internal Audit; Office of the General Counsel; Office of the Secretary; Grants Processing; Grants to Organizations; Individual Grants; Correspondence Control; Administrative Services; Facilities Management; Management Information Systems; Information Services; Archives; Records Services; Library; General Services; Information and Records Units; Financial Services; Office of Human Resources; Office of the Vice President; Fixed Income Investments; Private Equity; Equity Investments; Investment Administration
  - Organization Charts - Fiscal Year 1999 (3 folders), 1998 November-1999 December (Box 2, Folder 16-18)
    Folder 16:) -- Office of the President; Office of Communications; Program Division; Program Division; Office of the Vice President Asset Building and Community Development; Economic Development; Human Development and Reproductive Health; Office of Vice President -- Education, Media, Arts, and Culture; Education, Knowledge, and Religion; Media, Arts and Culture; Office of the Vice President Peace and Social Justice; Governance and Civil Society Program; Human Rights and International Cooperation Program; Office of Organizational Services; Office of Management Services; Grants Administration and Operations; Grants Administration - EMAC; Grants Administration - PSJ; Grants Administration - Assets; India, Nepal, and Sri Lanka; Indonesia; The Philippines; China; Vietnam; Russia and Eastern Europe; Andean Region and the Southern Cone; Mexico and Central America; Brazil; Eastern and Southern Africa; Middle East and North Africa; South Africa and Namibia Program; West Africa; Office of the Secretary, Legal, Human Resources, Financial and Administrative Services; Internal Audit; Office of the General Counsel; Office of the Secretary; Grants Processing; Correspondence Control; Administrative Services; Facilities Management; Management Information Systems; Information Services; Archives; Records Services; Library; General Services; Information and Records Units; Financial Services; Office of Human Resources; Investment Management Office of the Vice President; Fixed Income Investments; Private Equity; Equity Investments; Investment Administration
    Folder 17:) -- Office of the President; Office of Communications; Program Division; Office of the Vice President Asset Building and Community Development; Community and Resource Development; Economic Development; Human Development and Reproductive Health; Office of Vice President -- Education, Media, Arts, and Culture; Education, Knowledge, and Religion; Media, Arts and Culture; Office of the Vice President Peace and Social Justice; Governance and Civil Society Program; Human Rights and International Cooperation Program; Office of Organizational Services; Office of Management Services; Grants Administration and Operations; Grants Administration - EMAC; Grants Administration - PSJ; Grants Administration - Assets; India, Nepal, and Sri Lanka; Indonesia; The Philippines; China; Vietnam; Russia and Eastern Europe; Andean Region and the Southern Cone; Mexico and Central America; Brazil; Eastern and Southern Africa; Middle East and North Africa; South Africa and Namibia Program; West Africa; Office of the Secretary, Legal, Human Resources, Financial and Administrative Services; Internal Audit; Office of the General Counsel; Office of the Secretary; Grants Processing; Correspondence Control; Administrative Services; Facilities Management; Management Information Systems; Information Services; Archives; Records Services; Library; General Services; Information and Records Units; Financial Services; Office of Human Resources; Investment Management Office of the Vice President; Fixed Income Investments; Private Equity; Equity Investments; Investment Administration; Office of the President; Office of Communications; Program Division; Program Division; Office of the Vice President Asset Building and Community Development; Community and Resource Development; Economic Development; Human Development and Reproductive Health; Office of Vice President -- Education, Media, Arts, and Culture; Education, Knowledge, and Religion; Media, Arts and Culture; Office of the Vice President Peace and Social Justice; Governance and Civil Society Program; Human Rights and International Cooperation Program; Office of Organizational Services; Office of Management Services; Grants Administration and Operations; Grants Administration - EMAC; Grants Administration - PSJ; Grants Administration - Assets; India, Nepal, and Sri Lanka; Indonesia; The Philippines; China; Vietnam; Russia and Eastern Europe; Andean Region and the Southern Cone; Mexico and Central America; Brazil; Eastern and Southern Africa; Middle East and North Africa; South Africa and Namibia Program; West Africa; Office of the Secretary, Legal, Human Resources, Financial and Administrative Services; Internal Audit; Office of the General Counsel; Office of the Secretary; Grants Processing; Correspondence Control; Administrative Services; Facilities Management; Management Information Systems; Information Services; Archives; Records Services; Library; General Services; Information and Records Units; Financial Services; Office of Human Resources; Investment Management Office of the Vice President; Fixed Income Investments; Private Equity; Equity Investments; Investment Administration